Personal Information

Name Tom Runia

Place of Birth Leiden, The Netherlands
Address Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Telephone « please send an e-mail first »

E-mail tomrunia@gmail.com
Website https://tomrunia.github.io

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-runia-29448435/

Summary

I'm currently PhD student at QUVA Deep Vision lab, working on deep learning for computer vision. The focus of my research is on understanding and developing ideas around machine learning for video analysis. For more information, please see: https://ivi.fnwi.uva.nl/quva/

Education

2016 – Present Doctor of Philosophy (PhD.) in Artificial Intelligence

- QUVA Deep Vision Lab: University of Amsterdam and Qualcomm
- Deep Learning for Video Analysis
- Advisors: Cees Snoek and Arnold Smeulders

2013 – 2015 Master of Science (MSc.) in Computer Science

- Delft University of Technology
- Track: Intelligent Information Processing
- Thesis: High Speed Object Detection, supervised by Prof. Dr. Marco Loog
- Grade Point Average: 8.5/10 (Cum Laude, i.e. with honors)

2011 – 2012 Bridging Program to MSc. Computer Science

- Delft University of Technology
- 30 ECTs of courses in Computer Science and Software Engineering

2008 – 2011 Bachelor of Science (BSc.) in Applied Physics

- Delft University of Technology
- Thesis: Image Processing for Automated Cell Counting

2002 – 2008 Secondary School: Preparatory Scientific Education (VWO)

- Bonaventura College Leiden, The Netherlands
- Science and Technology complemented with Economics and Biology

Professional Experience

2014 – 2015 Research Intern at TomTom

Graduate internship on computer vision and machine learning. My research focused on high-speed object detection for autonomous driving applications. This involved the design and implementation of high-performance computer vision algorithms using C++ and GPU programming.

2013 – 2015 **Software Engineer** at **TamTam** (now Dept)

Tam Tam is in the top three of full-service internet agencies in The Netherlands. As a back-end developer at the operational services group I worked on some of the larger websites in the country.

2012 – 2013 Research Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Research assistant in the Quantitative Imaging group at TU Delft. One of my tasks involved the implementation of image processing algorithms in Java for super- resolution microscopy.

2009 – 2010 Research Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Innovative Design Delft is a small company focusing on data management systems and security. During my study, one day a week I worked on various projects as back-end developer.

Education

Awards

• Rewarded the **Ngi-NGN Award** in Computer Science for my MSc. Thesis (€1,000) (*From*: The Royal Holland Society of Sciences and Humanities)

Teaching

- BSc. Course Information Visualization at University of Amsterdam
- Supervising BSc. and MSc. student projects in Artificial Intelligence

Conference and Journal Reviewing

- PAMI: IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence
- NIPS: Neural Information Processing Systems
- CVPR: Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition
- ICCV: International Conference on Computer Vision
- ECCV: European Conference on Computer Vision
- ACM MM: ACM Multimedia

Extracurricular Activities

- Full-Time Board Member of the Study Association for Applied Physics (2012–2013)
- Entrepreneurial Study Trip to Silicon Valley (visiting Google, Apple, Twitch and more)
- Chairman of the Website Committee at the Physics Study Association (2010–2012)
- Chairman of the Electronic Committee at the Physics Study Association (2008–2012)
- Editor of the Quarterly Magazine "De Physics" for the Physics Study Association (2010)

Languages

- Dutch (Native Proficiency)
- English (Fluent Proficiency)
- **German** (Elementary Proficiency)
- French (Elementary Proficiency)